# 这也是一个显示刀工的菜
This is also a dish showing knife skills
# 豆腐的形状近似于雀舌的形状
The shape of tofu is like the tongue of sparrow
# 小菱形片
Small slice in diamond shape
# 用勺背慢慢趟
Lead gently with the back of spoon
# 平桥豆腐
Pingqiao Tofu
# 这得用大油 先得炼一下
We need lard. Gotta first cook it a bit
# 味儿还是有点腥味
There's still some gamey smell
# 但是你聪明
But you are smart
# 你加了葱姜了 你给耗一下
You left spring onion and ginger in it for a while
# 因为在淮扬菜里边
Because lard is widely used
# 用大油还是比较广泛
in Huaiyang cuisine
# 后来我给总结了一个是
I then made a summary
# 淮扬菜的大油
Lard in Huaiyang cuisine
# 川菜的红油
Red chili oil in Sichuan cuisine
# 粤菜的蚝油
Oyster sauce in Canton cuisine
# 鲁菜的什么油
And what in Shandong cuisine
# 葱油 回答正确
Scallion oil. Bingo
# 这就关小火慢慢炼
This has to be simmered with mild heat
# 配料说一下
Let's introduce the ingredients
# 蛋皮 香菇 用木耳也行
Egg roll wrapper, shiitake, black fungus is also fine
# 就配个颜色
Just for the color
# 这是虾干 这是熟的鸡肉
This is dried shrimp. This is cooked chicken
# 增加点鲜香的味道 四样东西
To add some umami taste and aroma. Four things
# 这道菜主要的主角还是豆腐
The leading role of this dish is tofu
# 它这是软滑嫩烫咸香
It is soft, silky, tender, hot, salty and has aroma
# 所以只要不影响
So as long as the side thing doesn't affect
# 主体这个味道的原料
the main flavor
# 咱们都可以用
It can be used
# 这上面一层老皮
There is a layer of skin on the top
# 得给它搞掉 有点硬
We gotta remove it. It's a bit hard
# 平桥豆腐主要体现在
Pingqiao Tofu is mainly presented by
# 豆腐的刀工上面
the knife skills
# 它要切成小的菱形
It has to be in small diamond shape
# 也叫雀舌片 跟舌头一样
Also called sparrow tongue slice. Like a tongue
# 斜刀第一片可以不要
First slice from tilted cutting can be thrown away
# 第二刀
Second slice
# 不能使劲往里按 得推着
Don't just push down the knife. You gotta send it there
# 它平行着进去
Let it slice parallelly
# 这最后一片就不要了
We will not use the last slice
# 你看都是小菱形片
You see. They are all in small diamond shape
# 小菱形
Small diamond shape
# 这是蛋皮
This is egg roll wrapper
# 咱们摊的时候放点（水）淀粉
When you make it, put some (water) starch in it
# 增加粘稠度 增加蛋皮的韧性
It increases the viscosity, makes the egg roll wrapper more tough
# 放盐么 不放盐
Do we add salt? No, no salt
# 切成小菱形
Cut to small diamond shape
# 猪油炒好了 炼的差不多了
Lard is ready. It's well simmered
# 把这葱炸到这种黄色
If you fry the scallion until it shows yellow like this
# 它会释放出这种葱的葱香味
it releases its own special aroma
# 没有炸到这个黄色还是不行的
It's not ready if you don't see this color
# 烧点水 还得把这豆腐烫一下
Boil some water. We gotta still heat up the tofu
# 加点盐 让它蛋白质凝固
Add some salt to let the protein coagulates
# 增加一些韧性
Increase the toughness
# 看咱们豆腐的形状
Look at the shape of the tofu
# 近似于雀舌的形状 小菱形片
Similar to the tongue of sparrow. Small diamond shape
# 切的还是比较薄
It's very thin
# 好了开锅就行了
It's ok once it's boiling
# 然后我们要加高汤
Then we add stock
# 今儿我们的高汤
The stock we use today
# 用的就是老饭骨的金汤
is the golden stock from our Lao Fan Gu
# 今天我这个菜不能要这么稠
Today's dish can't be this thick
# 大概兑了一个三倍的水
I added around three times amount of water
# 这汤还很鲜呐
The stock is very savory
# 然后调味 放点盐
Then we season it. A bit of salt
# 白胡椒粉
White pepper
# 胡椒粉还是在汤开之前最好放
White pepper is better put in before it's boiling
# 汤开之后它容易起疙瘩
Otherwise it might group into small pieces
# 出来了
Take it out
# 放在旁边 咱们炝个锅
Put it aside. Let's bring out the aroma
# 咱们炼的猪油要用上了
The simmered lard comes into play
# 倒点猪油
A bit of lard
# 然后呢 葱姜炝下锅
Then, scallion and ginger
# 出香味不能糊
Bring out the aroma without overcooking
# 然后把汤倒回来
Then pour back the stock
# 刚才调过味了咱就不用再调了
It has been seasoned so we don't have to season it again
# 然后把鸡肉 香菇
Then put chicken, shiitake
# 海米 鸡蛋皮（放进去）
Dried shrimp, egg roll wrapper (put them in)
# 然后咱们的豆腐
Then the tofu
# 豆腐焯完水之后不能单放
The boiled tofu can't be put aside without water
# 单放它就凝固了 粘一块了
Without water, it will stick together
# 沥完水迅速倒里
Quickly put it in to the pot after draining the water
# 然后用勺背慢慢搅开
Then slowly stir it with the back of spoon
# 小火煨它一分钟两分钟
Simmer it with mild heat for one or two minutes
# 让它入入味儿
For the flavor penetration
# 拿那什么
Take the dark soy sauce
# 拿老抽点一小筷头儿 好的
And put in a tiny bit of it. OK
# 咱们这道菜不需要特别的黄
The color of this dish doesn't have to be very yellowish
# 要点一点老抽中和一下颜色
We need a bit of dark soy sauce to neutralize it
# 刚刚好
Just right
# 这个咱们要放点味精
We need to put in some MSG
# 大约有0.5克 特别少 提个鲜味
Around 0.5 gram. Very little to promote the umami taste
# 这个水的温度一百度左右
The temperature is around 100 degree
# 所以它不至于把味精
So it will not turn MSG
# 变成其它的有害物质
into other harmful substance
# 开始勾芡 玉米淀粉
Add slurry. Corn starch
# 这一定要注意 慢慢勾
This has to be a careful step. Slowly
# 用勺背慢慢趟
Slowly lead it with the back of the spoon
# 趟劲儿太大了 这个豆腐就碎了
If you push it too hard, the tofu will be broken
# 最后还要打点（大）油
Finally some lard
# 最后成菜的特点看着不冒热气
The finished dish doesn't steam much
# 但是您入口肯定是特别的烫
But it will be very hot if you put it into your mouth
# 就来自于这里头油的温度 要推
It comes from the temperature of the oil. Gotta push it
# 还有一滴香油
And sesame oil
# 一定是少许的这么两滴
It must not be too much
# 多了就会抢掉味道
Otherwise it dominates the flavor over others
# 香菜
Cilantro
# 出盘
Finished
# 平桥豆腐
Pingqiao Tofu
# 其实这道菜
In fact, this dish
# 是一个传统的淮扬菜的老菜
is a traditional dish from Huaiyang cuisine
# 为什么叫平桥豆腐
Why is it called Pingqiao Tofu
# 它在淮安地区有个平桥 平桥镇
Because there is a Pingqiao in Huai'an area. Pingqiao town
# 这个菜来自于那儿
This dish comes from there
# 按当地传统的要有虾子
Based on the local tradition, shrimp roe is needed
# 现在因为虾子不好买
But it is hard to buy
# 要有虾子更加鲜美
It would be even more savory with shrimp roe
# 通过刚才的这种烹调的过程
By the cooking process
# 加上好的汤 清淡 滑润
with quality soup. Light. Skily and smooth
# 你看看似是一个
It looks like a
# 好像豆腐羹的这么一个烩的菜
thick tofu soup
# 但是它显示你勾芡的均匀
But it shows your evenly added slurry
# 火候的掌握
well controlled heat
# 你看那个菜的都在
You can see that added ingredients are
# 汁芡中间托浮着
supported by the soup and floating in it
# 而且粘稠适度 非常好
And the viscosity is very good
# 虽说看食材很普通
The ingredients seem to be ordinary
# 但是这里边从刀工到味道
But it is a dish with full attention
# 到色彩到呈现
from knife skills to flavor
# 就是讲究的一道菜
from color to presentation
# 今天隋坡再度把
Today, Po Sui recreated and
# 这道老菜给呈现出来
presented this traditional dish
# 好 谢谢二伯谢谢师父
Alright thank you Er Bai thank you master
# 这道菜也特别适合老年 也适合我
This dish is also very suitable for elderly people. Also for me
# 牙口不好的 小孩老人
People with less tough teeth. Children and elderly people